A Guide to the Henkel Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - A: NINETEENTH CENTURY CORRESPONDENTS
    - John George Schmucker* to Solomon and Paul Henkel, 1807-1821, n.d. (Box Box 2)
      Book Society wants to sell Shakespeare's works (22 volumes) for $ 9.00, the Collected Works of the King of Prussia (15 volumes) for $ 6.00, and Stiller's Heimweh for $ 5.00 (180[7] Jul 20); complaints about lack of correspondence and uncertainty of whether Henkel received the money (1808 Oct 17); receipt of newspaper and desire to receive copies of new pamphlets and books printed in New Market (1809 Apr 2); misunderstanding re the political views expressed by the writer and made public by Henkel, Republicans and Federalists are friends and calls the Democrats and Torys enemies of freedom (1809 Apr 15); announcement of a possible move to York, plans to preach in Woodstock, Shenandoah County, the first of August (1809 Jun 9); excerpts of "Protocols of the Lutheran Synod," Philadelphia, permission for Paul Henkel to do missionary work in Kentucky, Tennessee, Ohio, and Virginia, advice to Lutheran ministers to avoid camp meetings, and request for Paul Henkel's travel diary (1811 Jun 27); excerpts of Paul Henkel's missionary activities in South Carolina to be published by Mr. Helmuth in The Evangelical Magazine which needs 500 new subscribers to get started (1811 Aug 27); praises several Henkel publications (1812 Jan 11); remarks re The Evangelical Magazine and books ordered (1812 Apr 1); belief that the printing of the new Song Book should have been financially aided by the Synod (1812 Oct 17); business account and advice to David Henkel to enter the ministry (1812 Dec 18); possibility that Pastor Carpenter may go to Kentucky, and worries over possible victory by Napoleon Bonaparte (1813 Dec 3); Synodical expenses for Paul Henkel (1814 Jun 15); The Evangelical Magazine will be published yearly, and rejoicing re Napoleon Bonaparte's downfall (1814 Jul 23); accounts of [The Evangelical Magazine] taken care of by Pastor Muhlenberg in Reading (1817 Jun 11); asks if anyone in the area is a subscriber to the second part of Georg Schmucker's Prophetic History (1818 Dec 30); enclosure of a new children's book requested by Dr. Helmuth (1819 Apr 27); and acknowledgement of a letter (1821 Aug 31)
    - Gottlieb Shober* to Solomon Henkel, 1812 Dec 1 (Box Box 2)
      rumors of a Henkel Press business to be established in Lincolntown, North Carolina, and non-receipt of Honig Tropfen
    - Laurentz Wartman* to Solomon Henkel, n.y. Nov 20 (Box Box 2)
      re the need for printer's ink
    - Addison Wickes to Samuel G. Henkel, 1842 Mar 1 (Box Box 2)
      re the birth of a son, William Bentin, to [his wife ?] Jane, other family news, and the bonds of Jacob Savage
    - J.D. Williamson to [Samuel ?] Godfrey Henkel, 1863 Feb 15 (Box Box 2)
      re his problems with his uncle over the use of a farm
    - James and Alexander Wray to Solomon Henkel, 1842 Nov 30 (Box Box 2)
      re Jacob Savage's notes
    - Correspondence between Solomon Henkel and Postmaster General John McLean, 1824 (Box Box 2)
      re his duties as Postmaster at New Market
  - B: OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    - Correspondence of Dr. Casper O. Miller and other members of the Henkel Family Association, 1903-1940 (Box Box 2)
- SERIES II: MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS RE THE HENKEL FAMILY
  - Account Books, 1878-1894 (Box Box 2)
  - Business and Legal Papers, 1826-1940, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
  - Genealogical Material of the Henkel Family, 1917-1938, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of the Henkel Family, 1825-1834, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - New Market Academy, later called the New Market Polytechnic Institute, Minute and Record Books of the Trustees, 1838-1941; (2 Bound Volumes) (Box Box 3)
  - New Market Academy Proceedings and Subscription List for the New Building in Addition to the Academy, 1869-1870; (1 Bound Volume) (Box Box 3)
  - Notes re Doctors in the Henkel Family, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Photograph of Dr. [Casper Henkel], n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Photograph of Barbara Teter (d. 1814), wife of Jacob Henkel, copied from a pastel drawing, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous, 1931, n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Printed - A Biographical Sketch of Samuel G. Henkel, M.D. by Rev. Julius N. Stirewalt (Reprint), 1868 Mar, Apr (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - Carolinian Herald of Liberty, Religious and Political ... by David Henkel, 1821 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - Catalogue of the Virginia Female Institute Staunton, Virginia, 1883-1884 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - The Henkel Memorial, Second Series, 1913, 1914, 1919 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - A Historical Sketch of Sunday Schools by Rev. L.A. Fox, 1879 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - History of St. Michael's Evangelical Lutheran Church Germantown, Pennsylvania 1730-1905 by S. A. Ziegenfuss, 1905 Nov 12-14 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - "In Memoriam Rev. Socrates Henkel, D.D.", [ca. 1901 ?] (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - Miscellaneous, 1850-1939, n.d. (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - Proceedings of the Meeting of the Organization of the Evangelical Lutheran Concordia Synod of Virginia, 1868 May 23-26 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - The Relations of the Lutheran Church to the Denominations Around Us by C.P. Krauth, 1877 Dec 27 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - Report of the Proceedings of the Sixth Session of the Evangelical Lutheran Synod of Indiana, 1841 Oct 9-14 (Box Box 4)
  - Printed - A Review of the Testimony and Decisions in the Cases of Revs. J.B. Haskell and J.I. Miller, 1880 Jun 21-29 (Box Box 4)
  - Scholastic Reports for Samuel G. Henkel, 1822 (Box Box 4)
  - Tract on Religious Education (?) and Lutheran Doctrine in German, 1825 Apr-Sep (Box Box 4)
  - "Vorrede" by Silon A. Henkel, in German, 1827 Jul 25 (Box Box 4)
  - Woodcuts of Dr. Samuel G. Henkel and his signature (Box Box 4)
  - Woodcuts used in The Henkel Family Records No. 7, n.d. (Box Box 4)
- OVERSIZE FOLDER
  - [Shultz ?] Son & Rex to Solomon Henkel, [1842 ?] Dec 25
    re collecting on his account
  - Jacob Savage to Dr. Samuel G. Henkel, 1843 Feb 18
    re the payment of some bonds and other business matters
  - Genealogical chart showing the descendants of Rev. Andrew Henkel and Margaret Trout